mamasandpapas.co.uk 2014-04-20

# Privacy policy at Mamas & Papas

At Mamas & Papas, we are committed to protecting your personal information. We have published this Privacy Notice to ensure that you are fully aware of how and why we collect information from you and to whom such information is disclosed

References in this Privacy Notice to “we”, “us” and “our” means Mamas & Papas (US) Inc and its group companies. This Privacy Notice describes the types of personal information we may collect from you directly or through use of our website (“Personal Data”), how and when we may do so and what we will do with this Personal Data including who we may disclose it to. This Privacy Notice may be amended or added to from time to time. The latest version will appear on our website. However, we will notify you of material changes to this policy via email. We will only process Personal Data as set out in this Privacy Notice (as amended or added to) or otherwise notified to or agreed by you or as we are otherwise permitted to do in accordance with applicable law.

**A Special Note About The Privacy Of Minors.** Our site is designed and intended for use by adults over the age of 18. In compliance with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act and fair information practices, we will not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

## 1\. When do we collect Personal Data from you?

There are a number of occasions on which Personal Data may be collected from you. These include;

  * You purchase a product from us through our website or over the telephone
  * You visit our website without making a purchase
  * You provide us with your Personal Data for product registration
  * You provide us with your Personal Data to enable us to send you e-mail and/or postal marketing
  * You participate in a customer survey on-line or over the telephone
  * You enter a competition or prize draw on-line or over the telephone
  * You return a product to us for refund, exchange or repair
  * You make a complaint
  * You purchase a Mamas & Papas product through one of our appointed retailers where we deliver the product directly to you
  * You are an independent retailer of Mamas & Papas products and provide us with your Personal Data in the course of our trading relationship

## 2\. What Personal Data do we collect from you?

Depending on how and for what purpose we are collecting Personal Data from you; this will consist of one or more of the following items;

  * Name, address, telephone number(s) (home, work and cell) and e-mail address of the person making the purchase and, where different, the recipient
  * Name, address, telephone number(s) (home, work and cell) and e-mail address of any person other than the purchaser of the product from whom we are asked to collect any part of the payment due
  * Delivery and billing address
  * Collection address where a product is being returned
  * Credit or debit card details
  * Expected or actual date of birth and gender of the child
  * Information about any computer used to access our website (such as the IP address)
  * Information about siblings and lifestyle
  * Details of a complaint
  * Information collected when you visit our website (whether or not you make a purchase) by “cookies” or other internet technology as described in greater detail below

You must ensure all Personal Data you provide to us is true and accurate when provided. You agree not to impersonate any other person or to use a false name or personal details which you are not authorized to use.

## 3\. How do we use the Personal Data we collect from you?

We use the Personal Data you provide us with for the following purposes;

  * Fulfillment of the order you have placed with us (or with an appointed retailer) including processing your payment and delivering or making available for collection the purchased product
  * Registering your product
  * Sending you e-mail, postal and, when available, SMS marketing where you have subscribed for this such as our e-mail newsletter
  * Sending you vouchers
  * Processing a refund or exchange
  * Repairing your product
  * Sending you information in relation to your product
  * Entering you in the competition or prize draw for which you have completed an entry form
  * Investigating and responding to any complaint or other correspondence we receive from you
  * Monitoring and reviewing our products and service
  * Administering, developing and improving our website
  * Analyzing your browsing patterns to enable us to improve our website and your experience of it including selecting and tailoring products, services and special discounts we think you will be interested in
  * Monitoring customer traffic patterns and site usage to help us develop the design and layout of our website
  * Complying with our obligations under applicable law
  * Doing anything which is ancillary to or connected with any of the above purposes

## 4\. Who will we disclose your Personal Data to?

In order to fulfill the purposes set out above, we may disclose your Personal Data to the following third parties

  * The carrier who will deliver your product or collect it from you where we have arranged this
  * Someone to whom you have asked us to disclose your Personal Data or who we have good reason to believe you wish us to disclose your Personal Data to such as, for example, the recipient of a product you have purchased
  * Other companies in the same group of companies as Mamas & Papas (US) Inc
  * Any business we use for or in connection with any part of the order fulfillment process such as the processing of credit card payments
  * Any business that looks after or operates any of our computer servers which process Personal Data
  * Any business we use to produce or send out marketing material on our behalf
  * Where you opt in to receiving marketing material from a business other than another company in the Mamas & Papas group, that business
  * Any party to whom it is appropriate or necessary to disclose Personal Data in connection with any complaint or claim you make to us, such as our insurers or insurance brokers
  * Any party to whom we are required or entitled to disclose your Personal Data in accordance with applicable law or judicial process

We will only disclose such Personal Data to any third party as is necessary to enable them to carry out the function or purpose for which it is disclosed. For example, we will only disclose such Personal Data to a carrier as is necessary to enable them to deliver or collect your product

In addition, in the event that Mamas & Papas (or an affiliate) goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition, liquidation or sale of all or a portion of its assets, visitor information will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred.

Finally, we may, without your consent, access and disclose your personal information, any communications sent or received by you, and any other information that we may have about you as may be permitted or required by law, regulation, rule or court order; pursuant to requests from governmental, regulatory or administrative agencies or law enforcement authorities; or to prevent, investigate, identify persons or organizations potentially involved in, or take any action regarding suspected fraud, violations of our Terms of Service, or activity that appears to us to be illegal or may expose Mamas & Papas to legal liability. Additionally, we may disclose personal information in situations that we believe to be emergencies involving potential threats to the physical safety or any person or property if we believe that your information in any way relates to that threat.

## 5\. How do we protect your information

We take a range of reasonable technical and organizational measures which are intended to prevent unauthorized or unlawful processing or disclosure of Personal Data and accidental loss or destruction of, or damage to, Personal Data, and which are consistent with our legal obligations. The following are examples of the kinds of steps we take to protect your Personal Data.

We use software on our website which enables the encryption of sensitive information such as credit / debit card details during online transactions.

We require all third parties to whom any Personal Data is disclosed to keep it secure, treat it as confidential information and only use it for the purpose of providing their services and to fully comply with applicable law.

We follow strict security procedures in the storage, use and disclosure of Personal Data to prevent unauthorized access or processing. Our security procedures mean that we may occasionally request proof of identity before we are able to disclose Personal Data to you.

You should also be aware that despite our efforts, factors beyond our control may result in disclosure of personal information. Accordingly, we are not in a position to guarantee that your information will be secure under all circumstances.

## 6\. Where do we store your Personal Data?

Your Personal Data may be stored, used and otherwise processed within the UK and/or any other country(ies) of the European Economic Area (EEA). EEA countries are all member states of the European Union together with Norway, Iceland and Liechtenstein.

We may also store, use or otherwise process Personal Data outside the EEA. Data protection laws may not be as strong outside the EEA as they are in the EEA. Personal Data will not be transferred to a country outside the EEA unless (1) the country to which it is transferred is one which the European Commission considers to provide an adequate level of data protection or (2) the Personal Data is transferred to a United States company which has signed up to the Safe Harbour scheme or (3) the Personal Data is transferred to a company which is required by our contract with them only to deal with the data in accordance with our instructions and to maintain appropriate security to protect the Personal Data.

Our mail server is located in the United States of America. E-mail addresses, names and postal information are processed through this server. The third party who handles this processing has entered into a contract with us which meets the above requirements.

Credit card payments are processed by a separate company in the United States of America. This company has also entered into a contract with us which meets the above requirements.

## 7\. Security

**PCI Overview**

The Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS) is a security standard which at Tier 1 Certification and compliance ensures unbeatable security and protection of sensitive customer information including credit cards.

The requirements for Tier 1 Certification include:

  * Security management policies;
  * Security policies;
  * Security procedures;
  * Network architecture;
  * Software Design
  * Critical Protective Measures

Websites go through a rigorous INDEPENDENT audit and significant investment to attain Tier 1 PCI DSS certification. The purpose is to ensure that their customers' data is as safe as possible when they purchase products online.

Venda is the only global website provider to provide enterprise wide PCI DSS Tier 1 Certification. Visit www.venda.com for more information.

**Verified by Visa Overview**

Verified by Visa and MasterCard SecureCode, collectively also known as 3-D Secure, is an extra level of security developed by Visa and MasterCard to improve the security of payments and transactions offered to customers over the Internet. When you initiate a transaction using one of these card issuers you will be redirected to the website of your card-issuing bank to authorize the transaction. You will have to enter your password, or create one if you don’t already have one, which will then redirect you back to our site to complete your order. If you are creating a password, you can then use this password on any other site that uses 3-D Secure technology. Please note: this password is separate from the one you use to log in to our site.

## 8\. What information do we collect when you shop online and what are "cookies"?

When you shop on our website, we will ask you to input and will collect Personal Data from you such as your name, e-mail address, billing address, delivery address, telephone number, product selections, credit card or other payment information and a password. We may also collect information about where you are and have been on the internet (such as the URL you entered our website from, your IP address, domain types like .us and .com), your browser type and the country where your computer is located, the pages of our website that were viewed during your visit and any search terms that you entered on our website. We may collect this information even if you do not register with us

New technologies are emerging on the internet that helps us to deliver customized visitor experiences. In particular, there is a technology called "cookies" which may be used by us to provide you with customized information from our website. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which then may store it on your system. Cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website. Cookies also allow us to make our website more user friendly. We use cookies so that we can give you a better experience when you return to our website. We may also use third parties who will collect non personally identifiable data (such as the IP address of a user’s computer) to analyze site visits and carry out other similar activities. In the course of doing so, they may place their own cookies on your computer so that they can collect information about your visit. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies.

You do not have to accept cookies. You should read the information that came with your browser software to see how you can set up your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie which will give you the opportunity to decide whether to accept it. You may if you wish disable or delete such cookies through your internet browser. However, doing so may mean you will be unable to access our website or parts of it, your experience of our website may be adversely affected and/or you may not receive information which is relevant to your personal interests.

## 9\. What should you do if you no longer wish to receive marketing material from us?

When you create a shopping account while ordering online, you will be given the option of receiving information from Mamas & Papas online, by post, e-mail or, when available, via SMS, about products, promotions, special offers and other details which we feel may be of interest to you. In the event that you do not wish to receive such information, please ensure that you do not tick the appropriate box as you go through the registration process.

If you do not wish to receive further marketing information such as details of new products, promotions and special offers from us, please sign in to the My Account page on our website and change your communication preferences, call our Customer Relations team on 1-800-490-0331, or send an email to customercare.america@mamasandpapas.com headed “ unsubscribe” or alternatively write to us at UK Head Office, Customer Relations Department, Mamas & Papas (US) Inc, Colne Bridge Road, Huddersfield, United Kingdom, HD5 0RH

If you unsubscribe from email communications, it may take up to fourteen working days for this to take effect.

## 10\. Can you see and change the Personal Data we hold?

You are generally entitled to ask us what Personal Data of yours is being held or processed by us, for what purpose and to whom it may be or has been disclosed and otherwise to generally review and request changes to your Personal Data. We may charge a fee to respond to such a request. We promise to respond to your request within 40 days of receiving your written request and fee or as otherwise required by applicable law. In certain limited circumstances as permitted by applicable law, we may be entitled to refuse your request. If you believe that any of your Personal Data which we are processing is inaccurate or incorrect please contact us immediately. For any of the purposes outlined in this section 10, you may contact us via the contact information set forth below.

## 11\. Email a friend

E-mailing a friend enables you to easily notify your friends or family members about a product or service which may be of interest to them. We do not retain e-mail addresses provided by you when using this service.

## 12\. Your Consent

When you opt-in to communications from Mamas & Papas, you are consenting to the collection, processing and potential communication from other Mamas & Papas' companies.

## 13\. Links to Other Websites

Our website may contain links to other websites. When you use a link to go from this website to another, our privacy notice is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other website, including sites that have a link on or to our website, are subject to the privacy notice of that site. Be sure to read over that privacy notice before proceeding, as Mamas & Papas is not responsible for the privacy practices of such websites.

## 14\. Feedback

If you wish to contact us for any matter related to our Privacy Notice, please contact us on 1-800-490-0331. Alternatively you may e-mail us at customercare.america@mamasandpapas.com or write to UK Head Office Customer Relations Department, Mamas & Papas (US) Inc, Colne Bridge Road, Huddersfield, West Yorkshire, United Kingdom HD5 0RH

THIS PRIVACY NOTICE IS EFFECTIVE AS OF: 20 JUNE 2013
